The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: So today's lecture is on sorting.
教授：所以今天的演讲是关于分类的。
We'll be talking about specific sorting algorithms today.
今天我们将讨论特定的排序算法。
I want to start by motivating why
我想从动机开始
we're interested in sorting, which should be fairly easy.
我们对排序很感兴趣，这应该很容易。
Then I want to discuss a particular sorting
然后，我想讨论一个特定的排序
algorithm that's called insertion sort.
称为插入排序的算法。
That's probably the simplest sorting algorithm
那可能是最简单的排序算法
you can write, it's five lines of code.
您可以编写，这是五行代码。
It's not the best sorting algorithm
这不是最好的排序算法
that's out there and so we'll try and improve it.
在那里，因此我们将尝试对其进行改进。
We'll also talk about merge sort, which is a divide
我们还将讨论合并排序，这是一个划分
and conquer algorithm and that's going
和征服算法，这就是
to motivate the last thing that I want to spend time on,
激发我想花时间的最后一件事，
which is recurrences and how you solve recurrences.
这就是重复以及如何解决重复。
Typically the recurrences that we'll
通常情况下，
be looking at in double o six are going to come from divide
双看o六将来自鸿沟
and conquer problems like merge sort
并征服诸如合并排序之类的问题
but you'll see this over and over.
但您会一遍又一遍地看到它。
So let's talk about why we're interested in sorting.
因此，让我们谈谈为什么我们对排序感兴趣。
There's some fairly obvious applications
有一些相当明显的应用
like if you want to maintain a phone book,
例如，如果您想维护电话簿，
you've got a bunch of names and numbers corresponding
你有一堆对应的名字和数字
to a telephone directory and you want
到电话簿，您要
to keep them in sorted order so it's
使它们保持排序顺序
easy to search, mp3 organizers, spreadsheets, et cetera.
易于搜索，mp3组织者，电子表格等。
So there's lots of obvious applications.
因此，有许多显而易见的应用程序。
There's also some interesting problems
还有一些有趣的问题
that become easy once items are sorted.
对项目进行排序后，变得很容易。
One example of that is finding a median.
一个例子是求中位数。
So let's say that you have a bunch of items
假设您有一堆物品
in an array a zero through n and a zero through n
在数组中，零到n和零到n
contains n numbers and they're not sorted.
包含n个数字，但未排序。
When you sort, you turn this into b 0
排序时，将其变成b 0
through n, where if it's just numbers, then
到n，如果只是数字，则
you may sort them in increasing order or decreasing order.
您可以按升序或降序对它们进行排序。
Let's just call it increasing order for now.
现在我们就称其为递增顺序。
Or if they're records, and they're not numbers,
或者如果它们是记录而不是数字，
then you have to provide a comparison function
那么你必须提供一个比较功能
to determine which record is smaller than another record.
确定哪个记录比另一个记录小。
And that's another input that you
这是你的另一项投入
have to have in order to do the sorting.
必须要进行排序。
So it doesn't really matter what the items are
所以什么东西真的没关系
as long as you have the comparison function.
只要您具有比较功能。
Think of it as less than or equal to.
认为它小于或等于。
And if you have that and it's straightforward,
如果有的话很简单，
obviously, to check that 3 is less than 4, et cetera.
显然，要检查3是否小于4，等等。
But it may be a little more complicated
但这可能有点复杂
for more sophisticated sorting applications.
适用于更复杂的分拣应用。
But the bottom line is that if you have your algorithm that
但最重要的是，如果您有算法
takes a comparison function as an input,
将比较功能作为输入，
you're going to be able to, after a certain amount of time,
经过一段时间后，您将能够
get B 0 n.
得到B 0 n。
Now if you wanted to find the median of the set of numbers
现在，如果您想找到一组数字的中位数
that were originally in the array A,
最初在数组A中
what would you do once you have the sorted array B?
拥有排序的数组B后，您将怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Isn't there a more efficient algorithm for median?
听众：有没有更有效的中位数算法？
PROFESSOR: Absolutely.
教授：当然可以。
But this is sort of a side effect of having a sorted list.
但这是排序列表的一种副作用。
If you happen to have a sorted list,
如果您碰巧有一个排序列表，
there's many ways that you could imagine
您可以想象有很多方式
building up a sorted list.
建立一个排序列表。
One way is you have something that's completely unsorted
一种方法是您拥有完全未分类的东西
and you run insertion sort or merge sort.
然后运行插入排序或合并排序。
Another way would be to maintain a sorted list as you're
另一种方法是在您
getting items put into the list.
将物品放入清单。
So if you happened to have a sorted list
因此，如果您碰巧有一个排序列表
and you need to have this sorted list for some reason,
并且出于某种原因，您需要具有此排序列表，
the point I'm making here is that finding the median
我要说的是找到中位数
is easy.
简单。
And it's easy because all you have to do
这很容易，因为您要做的一切
is look at-- depending on whether n is odd
看-取决于n是否为奇数
or even-- look at B of n over 2.
甚至-看n超过2的B.
That would give you the median because you'd
那会给你中位数，因为你会
have a bunch of numbers that are less than that
有一堆小于这个数字
and the equal set of numbers that are greater than that,
和相等的一组数字，大于
which is the definition of median.
这是中位数的定义。
So this is not necessarily the best way, as you pointed out,
因此，正如您所指出的，这不一定是最好的方法，
of finding the median.
找到中位数
But it's constant time if you have a sorted list.
但是，如果您有一个已排序的列表，这将是固定时间。
That's the point I wanted to make.
这就是我要提出的重点。
There are other things that you could do.
您还可以做其他事情。
And this came up in Erik's lecture,
在埃里克的演讲中，
which is the notion of binary search-- finding
二进制搜索的概念-查找
an element in an array-- a specific element.
数组中的元素-特定元素。
You have a list of items-- again a 0 through n.
您有一个项目列表-也是0到n。
And you're looking for a specific number or item.
您正在寻找一个特定的编号或项目。
You could, obviously, scan the array,
显然，您可以扫描阵列，
and that would take you linear time to find this item.
这将花费您线性时间才能找到该物品。
If the array happened to be sorted,
如果数组碰巧被排序，
then you can find this in logarithmic time
然后您可以在对数时间找到它
using what's called binary search.
使用所谓的二进制搜索。
Let's say you're looking for a specific item.
假设您要寻找特定商品。
Let's call it k.
我们称它为k。
Binary search, roughly speaking, would
粗略地说，二进制搜索会
work like-- you go compare k to, again, B of n over 2,
就像-您将k再次与n等于2的B进行比较
and decide, given that B is sorted,
并确定，鉴于B已排序，
you get to look at 1/2 of the array.
您可以看一下数组的1/2。
If B of n over 2 is not exactly k, then-- well,
如果n大于2的B不完全是k，那么-
if it's exactly k you're done.
如果恰好是k，那么您就完成了。
Otherwise, you look at the left half.
否则，请看左半部分。
You do your divide and conquer paradigm.
您可以进行分而治之。
And you can do this in logarithmic time.
您可以在对数时间内完成此操作。
So keep this in mind, because binary search
因此请记住这一点，因为二进制搜索
is going to come up in today's lecture
在今天的演讲中
and again in other lectures.
在其他讲座中
It's really a great paradigm of divide
这确实是一个很好的鸿沟范式
and conquer-- probably the simplest.
征服-可能是最简单的。
And it, essentially, takes something
从本质上讲，它需要一些东西
that's linear-- a linear search--
这是线性的-线性搜索-
and turns it into logarithmic search.
并将其转换为对数搜索。
So those are a couple of problems
所以这是几个问题
that become easy if you have a sorted list.
如果您有一个排序列表，这将变得很容易。
And there's some not so obvious applications
还有一些不太明显的应用
of sorting-- for example, data compression.
排序-例如数据压缩。
If you wanted to compress a file,
如果您要压缩文件，
one of the things that you could do is to--
您可以做的一件事是-
and it's a set of items-- you could sort the items.
这是一组项目-您可以对这些项目进行排序。
And that automatically finds duplicates.
并自动查找重复项。
And you could say, if I have 100 items that are all identical,
你可能会说，如果我有100个完全相同的项目，
I'm going to compress the file by representing the item once
我将通过一次表示项目来压缩文件
and, then, having a number associated
然后，关联一个数字
with the frequency of that item-- similar to what
与该项目的频率相似
document distance does.
文件距离呢。
Document distance can be viewed as a way
可以将文档距离视为一种方式
of compressing your initial input.
压缩您的初始输入。
Obviously, you lose the works of Shakespeare or whatever it was.
显然，您会失去莎士比亚的作品或其他作品。
And it becomes a bunch of words and frequencies.
它变成了一堆单词和频率。
But it is something that compresses the input
但这会压缩输入
and gives you a different representation.
并为您提供了不同的表示形式。
And so people use sorting as a subroutine in data compression.
因此，人们将排序用作数据压缩中的子例程。
Computer graphics uses sorting.
计算机图形学使用排序。
Most of the time, when you render
大多数时候，当您渲染
scenes in computer graphics, you have many layers
计算机图形学中的场景，您有很多层
corresponding to the scenes.
对应于场景。
It turns out that, in computer graphics,
事实证明，在计算机图形学中，
most of the time you're actually rendering
大多数情况下，您实际上是在渲染
front to back because, when you have a big opaque
从前到后，因为当您不透明时
object in front, you want to render that first,
前面的对象，您要先渲染
so you don't have to worry about everything that's
这样您就不必担心一切
occluded by this big opaque object.
被这个大的不透明物体遮挡。
And that makes things more efficient.
这使事情变得更有效率。
And so you keep things sorted front to back,
因此，您可以将事情从头到尾排序，
most of the time, in computer graphics rendering.
大多数时候，是在计算机图形渲染中。
But some of the time, if you're worried about transparency,
但是有时候，如果您担心透明度，
you have to render things back to front.
您必须将内容渲染回前端。
So typically, you have sorted lists
因此，通常情况下，您对列表进行了排序
corresponding to the different objects in both orders--
对应于两个订单中的不同对象-
both increasing order and decreasing order.
递增顺序和递减顺序。
And you're maintaining that.
而您正在维护。
So sorting is a real important subroutine
所以排序是一个真正重要的子程序
in pretty much any sophisticated application you look at.
几乎可以在任何复杂的应用程序中看到。
So it's worthwhile to look at the variety of sorting
因此，值得一看的是各种分类
algorithms that are out there.
现有的算法。
And we're going to do some simple ones, today.
今天，我们将做一些简单的事情。
But if you go and look at Wikipedia
但是如果你去看维基百科
and do a Google search, there's all sorts
并进行Google搜索，种类繁多
of sorts like cocktail sort, and bitonic sort,
像鸡尾酒式和双调式
and what have you.
还有你呢
And there's reasons why each of these sorting algorithms exist.
并且存在每种分类算法都存在的原因。
Because in specific cases, they end up
因为在特定情况下，它们最终会
winning on types of inputs or types of problems.
在投入类型或问题类型上获胜。
So let's take a look at our first sorting algorithm.
因此，让我们看一下第一个排序算法。
I'm not going to write code but it will be in the notes.
我不会编写代码，但是会在注释中。
And it is in your document distance Python files.
它在您的文档中距离Python文件。
But I'll just give you pseudocode here
但是我只给你伪代码
and walk through what insertion sort looks like
并浏览一下插入排序的样子
because the purpose of describing
因为描述的目的
this algorithm to you is to analyze its complexity.
这个算法对您来说就是分析它的复杂性。
We need to do some counting here,
我们需要在这里做一些计数
with respect to this algorithm, to figure out
关于这个算法，找出
how fast it's going to run in and what the worst case
它要运行多快，最坏的情况是什么
complexity is.
复杂性是。
So what is insertion sort?
那么什么是插入排序？
For i equals 1, 2, through n, given an input to be sorted,
对于i等于1、2到n，给定要排序的输入，
what we're going to do is we're going to insert A of i
我们要做的是插入i的A
in the right position.
在正确的位置。
And we're going to assume that we
我们将假设我们
are sort of midway through the sorting process, where
在排序过程中处于中间位置，
we have sorted A 0 through i minus 1.
我们将A 0排序为i减去1。
And we're going to expand this to this array
我们将扩展到这个数组
to have i plus 1 elements.
让我加1个元素。
And A of i is going to get inserted
我的A将被插入
into the correct position.
正确的位置。
And we're going to do this by pairwise swaps
我们将通过成对交换来做到这一点
down to the correct position for the number that is initially
下降到最初数字的正确位置
in A of i.
在我的A中
So let's go through an example of this.
因此，让我们来看一个例子。
We're going to sort in increasing order.
我们将按升序排序。
Just have six numbers.
只要有六个数字。
And initially, we have 5, 2, 4, 6, 1, 3.
最初，我们有5、2、4、6、1、3。
And we're going to take a look at this.
我们将对此进行研究。
And you start with the index 1, or the second element,
然后从索引1或第二个元素开始，
because the very first element-- it's a single element
因为第一个元素-它是一个元素
and it's already sorted by definition.
并且已经按定义排序。
But you start from here.
但是你从这里开始。
And this is what we call our key.
这就是我们所谓的关键。
And that's essentially a pointer to where we're at, right now.
从本质上讲，这是目前我们所处位置的指针。
And the key keeps moving to the right
而且钥匙一直向右移动
as we go through the different steps of the algorithm.
当我们经历算法的不同步骤时。
And so what you do is you look at this
所以你要做的就是看这个
and you have-- this is A of i.
而您有-这是i的A。
That's your key.
那是你的钥匙。
And you have A of 0 to 0, which is 5.
您的A为0到0，即5。
And since we want to sort in increasing order,
由于我们想按升序排序，
this is not sorted.
这没有排序。
And so we do a swap.
因此，我们进行了交换。
So what this would do in this step is to do a swap.
因此，此步骤将要做的是交换。
And we would go obtain 2, 5, 4, 6, 1, 3.
然后我们将获得2、5、4、6、1、3。
So all that's happened here, in this step-- in the very
所以所有的事情都在这里发生了
first step where the key is in the second position--
钥匙位于第二位置的第一步-
is one swap happened.
是一次交换发生了。
Now, your key is here, at item 4.
现在，您的钥匙在这里，第4项。
Again, you need to put 4 into the right spot.
同样，您需要将4放置在正确的位置。
And so you do pairwise swaps.
因此，您进行成对交换。
And in this case, you have to do one swap.
在这种情况下，您必须进行一次交换。
And you get 2, 4, 5.
然后您得到2、4、5。
And you're done with this iteration.
这样的迭代就完成了。
So what happens here is you have 2, 4, 5, 6, 1, 3.
所以这里发生的是您有2，4，5，6，1，3。
And now, the key is over here, at 6.
现在，关键就在这里，即6点。
Now, at this point, things are kind of easy,
现在，这很容易
in the sense that you look at it and you say, well, I
从某种意义上说，你说，嗯，我
know this part is already started.
知道这部分已经开始。
6 is greater than 5.
6大于5。
So you have to do nothing.
因此，您无需执行任何操作。
So there's no swaps that happen in this step.
因此，在此步骤中不会发生任何交换。
So all that happens here is you're
所以这里发生的一切就是你
going to move the key to one step to the right.
将键向右移动一步。
So you have 2, 4, 5, 6, 1, 3.
所以你有2、4、5、6、1、3
And your key is now at 1.
现在您的密钥是1。
Here, you have to do more work.
在这里，您必须做更多的工作。
Now, you see one aspect of the complexity of this algorithm--
现在，您将看到此算法复杂性的一个方面-
given that you're doing pairwise swaps-- the way
鉴于您正在进行成对交换-
this algorithm was defined, in pseudocode, out there, was I'm
这个算法是用伪代码定义的，我在
going to use pairwise swaps to find the correct position.
将使用成对掉期来查找正确的位置。
So what you're going to do is you're
所以你要做的就是
going to have to swap first 1 and 6.
必须先交换1和6。
And then you'll swap-- 1 is over here.
然后您将交换-1在这里。
So you'll swap this position and that position.
因此，您将交换该职位和该职位。
And then you'll swap-- essentially,
然后您将交换-本质上，
do 4 swaps to get to the point where you have
进行4次互换以达到您拥有的位置
1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 3.
1，2，4，5，6，3。
So this is the result.
所以这就是结果。
1, 2, 4, 5, 6, 3.
1，2，4，5，6，3。
And the important thing to understand, here,
这里要了解的重要一点是
is that you've done four swaps to get 1
是您已经进行了四次交换以获得1
to the correct position.
到正确的位置。
Now, you could imagine a different data structure
现在，您可以想象一个不同的数据结构
where you move this over there and you shift them
你把它移到那边，然后转移它们
all to the right.
所有的权利。
But in fact, that shifting of these four elements
但实际上，这四个要素的转移
is going to be computed in our model as four
将在我们的模型中计算为四个
operations, or four steps, anyway.
操作或四个步骤。
So there's no getting away from the fact
所以没有远离事实
that you have to do four things here.
您必须在这里做四件事。
And the way the code that we have for insertion sort
以及我们插入代码的方式
does this is by using pairwise swaps.
这是通过使用成对交换来实现的。
So we're almost done.
这样我们就快完成了。
Now, we have the key at 3.
现在，我们将密钥设置为3。
And now, 3 needs to get put into the correct position.
现在，需要将3个放到正确的位置。
And so you've got to do a few swaps.
因此，您必须进行一些交换。
This is the last step.
这是最后一步。
And what happens here is 3 is going to get swapped with 6.
而这里发生的是3将与6交换。
And then 3 needs to get swapped with 5.
然后3需要与5交换。
And then 3 needs to get swapped with 4.
然后3需要与4交换。
And then, since 3 is greater than 2, you're done.
然后，由于3大于2，您就完成了。
So you have 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
所以你有1，2，3，4，5，6
And that's it.
就是这样。
So, analysis.
因此，分析。
How many steps do I have?
我要执行几个步骤？
AUDIENCE: n squared?
听众：n平方？
PROFESSOR: No, how many steps do I have?
教授：不，我有多少步骤？
I guess that wasn't a good question.
我想这不是一个好问题。
If I think of a step as being a movement of the key,
如果我认为一步是钥匙的运动，
how many steps do I have?
我要执行几个步骤？
I have theta n steps.
我有步骤。
And in this case, you can think of it as n minus 1 steps,
在这种情况下，您可以将其视为n减去1步，
since you started with 2.
自从2开始
But let's just call it theta n steps,
但是，让我们称其为“一步”
in terms of key positions.
在关键职位上。
And you're right.
而且你是对的。
It is n square because, at any given step,
它是n平方，因为在任何给定步骤中，
it's quite possible that I have to do theta n work.
我很有可能必须做theta n工作。
And one example is this one, right here,
一个例子就是这个，就在这里，
where I had to do four swaps.
我必须做四个交换。
And in general, you can construct a scenario
通常，您可以构建一个方案
where, towards the end of the algorithm,
在算法的末尾，
you'd have to do theta n work.
您需要做theta n工作。
But if you had a list that was reverse sorted.
但是，如果您有一个被反向排序的列表。
You would, essentially, have to do, on an average n
从本质上讲，您实际上必须平均
by two swaps as you go through each of the steps.
在完成每个步骤时，需要进行两次互换。
And that's theta n.
那就是theta n。
So each step is theta n swaps.
因此，每一步都是theta n交换。
And when I say swaps, I could also
当我说交换时，我也可以
say each step is theta n compares and swaps.
说每个步骤都是比较和交换。
And this is going to be important
这将很重要
because I'm going to ask you an interesting question
因为我要问你一个有趣的问题
in a minute.
在一分钟内。
But let me summarize.
但让我总结一下。
What I have here is a theta n squared algorithm.
我在这里有一个theta n平方算法。
The reason this is a theta n squared
这是theta n平方的原因
algorithm is because I have theta n steps
算法是因为我有theta n步骤
and each step is theta n.
每一步都是theta n。
When I'm counting, what am I counting
当我数数时，我在数数
it terms of operations?
它的运营条款？
The assumption here-- unspoken assumption--
这里的假设-不言而喻的假设-
has been that an operation is a compare and a swap
一直是一个操作是一个比较和交换
and they're, essentially, equal in cost.
从本质上讲，它们的成本是相等的。
And in most computers, that's true.
在大多数计算机上都是如此。
You have a single instruction and, say, the x86
您只有一条指令，例如x86
or the MIPS architecture that can do a compare,
或可以进行比较的MIPS架构，
and the same thing for swapping registers.
与交换寄存器的操作相同。
So perfectly reasonably assumption
如此完全合理的假设
that compares and swaps for numbers
比较并交换数字
have exactly the same cost.
费用完全相同。
But if you had a record and you were comparing records,
但是，如果您有记录，并且正在比较记录，
and the comparison function that you used for the records was
您用于记录的比较功能是
in itself a method call or a subroutine,
本身就是方法调用或子例程，
it's quite possible that all you're doing
您正在做的事情很有可能
is swapping pointers or references to do the swap,
正在交换指针或引用以进行交换，
but the comparison could be substantially more expensive.
但比较起来可能会贵得多。
Most of the time-- and we'll differentiate
大多数时候-我们将与众不同
if it becomes necessary-- we're going
如果有必要-我们要
to be counting comparisons in the sorting algorithms
计数排序算法中的比较
that we'll be putting out.
我们将推出。
And we'll be assuming that either comparison swaps are
并且我们假设比较交换是
roughly the same or that compares are--
大致相同或比较为-
and we'll say which one, of course-- that compares
我们当然会说哪个
are substantially more expensive than swaps.
比掉期要贵得多。
So if you had either of those cases for insertion sort,
因此，如果您有两种情况需要插入排序，
you have a theta n squared algorithm.
您有一个theta n平方算法。
You have theta n squared compares
你有平方的比较
and theta n squared swaps.
和theta n平方掉期。
Now, here's a question.
现在，这是一个问题。
Let's say that compares are more expensive than swaps.
假设比较比交换更昂贵。
And so, I'm concerned about the theta
因此，我担心theta
n squared comparison cost.
n比较成本的平方。
I'm not as concerned, because of the constant factors involved,
由于涉及的因素不断，我并不担心，
with the theta n squared swap cost.
与theta n平方掉期成本。
This is a question question.
这是一个问题。
What's a simple fix-- change to this algorithm that
什么是简单的解决方法-对此算法进行更改即可
would give me a better complexity in the case
在这种情况下会给我带来更好的复杂性
where compares are more expensive,
比较起来比较贵的地方
or I'm only looking at the complexity of compares.
或者我只是在看比较的复杂性。
So the theta whatever of compares.
因此，theta不论比较。
Anyone?
任何人？
Yeah, back there.
是的，回到那里。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: You could compare with the middle.
教授：您可以与中间人进行比较。
What did I call it?
我叫什么
I called it something.
我给它打电话。
What you just said, I called it something.
你刚才说的，我给它打电话。
AUDIENCE: Binary search.
受众：二进制搜索。
PROFESSOR: Binary search.
教授：二进制搜索。
That's right.
那就对了。
Two cushions for this one.
这个有两个垫子。
So you pick them up after lecture.
因此，您可以在演讲后接他们。
So you're exactly right.
所以你说的很对。
You got it right.
你做对了。
I called it binary search, up here.
我称它为二进制搜索，就在这里。
And so you can take insertion sort
这样您就可以进行插入排序
and you can sort of trivially turn it into a theta n log n
您可以轻松地将其变成theta n log n
algorithm if we are talking about n
如果我们在谈论n
being the number of compares.
是比较数。
And all you have to do to do that is to say,
而您要做的就是说，
you know what, I'm going to replace
你知道吗，我要替换
this with binary search.
这与二进制搜索。
And you can do that-- and that was the key observation--
您可以做到这一点-这是关键的观察-
because A of 0 through i minus 1 is already sorted.
因为从0到i减去1的A已被排序。
And so you can do binary search on that part of the array.
因此，您可以在数组的该部分上执行二进制搜索。
So let me just write that down.
所以，让我写下来。
Do a binary search on A of 0 through i minus 1,
对A的0到i减去1进行二进制搜索。
which is already sorted.
已经排序。
And essentially, you can think of it as theta log i time,
本质上，您可以将其视为时间的theta日志，
and for each of those steps.
对于每个步骤。
And so then you get your theta n log n theta n log
这样您就可以得到theta n log n theta n log
n in terms of compares.
n在比较方面。
Does this help the swaps for an array data structure?
这是否有助于交换数组数据结构？
No, because binary search will require insertion
否，因为二进制搜索将需要插入
into A of 0 though i minus 1.
虽然我减去1.变成0的A。
So here's the problem.
这就是问题所在。
Why don't we have a full-fledged theta n log n algorithm,
为什么我们没有完善的theta n log n算法，
regardless of the cost of compares or swaps?
不管比较或掉期的成本？
We don't quite have that.
我们还没有。
We don't quite have that because we need to insert our A of i
我们还没有，因为我们需要插入我的A
into the right position into A of 0 through i minus 1.
通过i减去1到A的正确位置
You do that if you have an array structure,
如果您具有数组结构，则可以这样做
it might get into the middle.
它可能会进入中间。
And you have to shift things over to the right.
而且您必须将事情移到右边。
And when you shift things over to the right,
当您将内容移至右侧时，
in the worst case, you may be shifting a lot of things
在最坏的情况下，您可能会转移很多东西
over to the right.
在右边。
And that gets back to worst case complexity of theta n.
这又回到了最坏情况下的θn复杂性。
So a binary search in insertion sort
所以在插入排序中进行二进制搜索
gives you theta n log n for compares.
给您then n log n进行比较。
But it's still theta n squared for swaps.
但这仍然是交换交易的平方。
So as you can see, there's many varieties
如您所见，有很多品种
of sorting algorithms.
排序算法。
We just looked at a couple of them.
我们只是看了几个。
And they were both insertion sort.
而且它们都是插入排序。
The second one that I just put up
我刚提出的第二个
is, I guess, technically called binary insertion sort
我猜是技术上称为二进制插入排序
because it does binary search.
因为它执行二进制搜索。
And the vanilla insertion sort is
和香草插入排序是
the one that you have the code for in the doc dis program,
您在doc dis程序中拥有代码的代码，
or at least one of the doc dis files.
或至少一个doc dis文件。
So let's move on and talk about a different algorithm.
因此，让我们继续讨论另一种算法。
So what we'd like to do, now-- this class
所以我们现在想做什么
is about constant improvement.
关于持续改进。
We're never happy.
我们永远不会幸福。
We always want to do a little bit better.
我们一直想做得更好。
And eventually, once we run out of room
最终，一旦我们的房间用完了
from an asymptotic standpoint, you
从渐近的角度来看，
take these other classes where you try and improve
尝试其他这些课程并加以改进
constant factors and get 10%, and 5%, and 1%,
常数因子得到10％，5％和1％，
and so on, and so forth.
等等等等。
But we'll stick to improving asymptotic complexity.
但是我们将坚持改善渐近复杂性。
And we're not quite happy with binary insertion sort
而且我们对二进制插入排序不满意
because, in the case of numbers, our binary insertion sort
因为，对于数字，我们的二进制插入排序
has theta n squared complexity, if you look at swaps.
如果您查看交换，则具有平方复杂度。
So we'd like to go find an algorithm that is theta n log
因此，我们想找到一种算法，即
n.
。
And I guess, eventually, we'll have to stop.
我想，最终，我们将不得不停止。
But Erik will take care of that.
但是Erik会照顾好这个。
There's a reason to stop.
有停止的理由。
It's when you can prove that you can't do any better.
这是您可以证明自己无法做得更好的时候。
And so we'll get to that, eventually.
因此，我们最终将解决这个问题。
So merge sort is also something that you've probably seen.
因此，合并排序也是您可能已经看到的东西。
But there probably will be a couple
但是可能会有一对
of subtleties that come out as I describe this algorithm that,
我描述此算法时会发现一些微妙之处，
hopefully, will be interesting to those of you who already
希望对那些已经
know merge sort.
知道合并排序。
And for those of you who don't, it's a very pretty algorithm.
对于那些不这样做的人来说，这是一个非常漂亮的算法。
It's a standard recursion algorithm-- recursive
这是标准的递归算法-递归
algorithm-- similar to a binary search.
算法-类似于二进制搜索。
What we do, here, is we have an array, A. We split it
在这里，我们要做的是有一个数组A。我们将其拆分
into two parts, L and R. And essentially, we kind of
分为L和R两部分。从本质上讲，我们有点
do no work, really.
没事，真的。
In terms of the L and R in the sense that we just call,
就我们刚才所说的L和R而言，
we keep splitting, splitting, splitting.
我们不断分裂，分裂，分裂。
And all the work is done down at the bottom
所有工作都在底部完成
in this routine called merge, where we are merging
在这个称为合并的例程中，我们正在合并
a pair of elements at the leaves.
叶子上的一对元素。
And then, we merge two pairs and get four elements.
然后，我们合并两对并获得四个元素。
And then we merge four tuples of elements, et cetera,
然后我们合并元素的四个元组，等等
and go all the way up.
并一直上升。
So while I'm just saying L terms into L prime, out here,
因此，虽然我只是说L个词成L个质数，但在这里，
there's no real explicit code that you
没有真正的显式代码
can see that turns L into L prime.
可以看到将L变成L素数。
It happens really later.
真的会在以后发生。
There's no real sorting code, here.
这里没有真正的排序代码。
It happens in the merge routine.
它发生在合并例程中。
And you'll see that quite clearly
而且您会清楚地看到
when we run through an example.
当我们通过一个例子。
So you have L and R turn into L prime and R prime.
因此，您有L和R变成L素数和R素数。
And what we end up getting is a sorted array, A.
我们最终得到的是一个排序的数组A。
And we have what's called a merge routine that
我们有一个所谓的合并例程
takes L prime and R prime and merges them
接受L素数和R素数并将它们合并
into the sorted array.
进入排序后的数组。
So at the top level, what you see is split into two,
因此，在顶层，您看到的内容分为两部分，
and do a merge, and get to the sorted array.
并进行合并，然后进入排序后的数组。
The input is of size n.
输入的大小为n。
You have two arrays of size n over 2.
您有两个大小为n大于2的数组。
These are two sorted arrays of size n over 2.
这是大小为n大于2的两个排序数组。
And then, finally, you have a sorted array of size n.
然后，最后，您得到大小为n的排序数组。
So if you want to follow the recursive of execution
因此，如果要遵循递归执行
of this in a small example, then you'll
在一个小例子中，那么您将
be able to see how this works.
能够看到它是如何工作的。
And we'll do a fairly straightforward example
我们将做一个非常简单的例子
with 8 elements.
有8个元素。
So at the top level-- before we get there, merge
因此，在顶层-在我们到达那里之前，先合并
is going to assume that you have two sorted arrays,
假设您有两个排序的数组，
and merge them together.
并合并在一起。
That's the invariant in merge sort, or for the merge routine.
这是合并排序或合并例程中的不变式。
It assumes the inputs are sorted-- L and R. Actually
假设输入已排序-L和R。实际上
I should say, L prime and R prime.
我应该说，L素数和R素数。
So let's say you have 20, 13, 7, and 2.
假设您有20、13、7和2。
You have 12, 11, 9, and 1.
您有12、11、9和1。
And this could be L prime.
这可能是L素数。
And this could be R prime.
这可能是R素数。
What you have is what we call a two finger algorithm.
您拥有的就是所谓的两指算法。
And so you've got two fingers and each of them
因此，您有两个手指，每个手指
point to something.
指向某事。
And in this case, one of them is pointing
在这种情况下，其中一个指向
to L. My left finger is pointing to L prime,
我的左手指指向L素数，
or some element L prime.
或某些元素L素数。
My right finger is pointing to some element in R prime.
我的右手指指向R素数中的某个元素。
And I'm going to compare the two elements
我将比较这两个元素
that my fingers are pointing to.
我的手指指向的地方。
And I'm going to choose, in this case,
在这种情况下，我将选择
the smaller of those elements.
这些元素中较小的一个。
And I'm going to put them into the sorted array.
我将它们放入已排序的数组中。
So start out here.
所以从这里开始。
Look at that and that.
看那个那个。
And I compared 2 and 1.
我比较了2和1。
And which is smaller?
哪个更小？
1 is smaller.
1较小。
So I'm going to write 1 down.
所以我要写下1。
This is a two finger algo for merge.
这是一个用于合并的两指算法。
And I put 1 down.
我放下1。
When I put 1 down, I had to cross out 1.
当我放下1时，我必须剔除1。
So effectively, what happens is-- let
如此有效地发生了-
me just circle that instead of crossing it out.
我只是圈出它而不是划掉它。
And my finger moves up to 9.
我的手指向上移动到9。
So now I'm pointing at 2 and 9.
所以现在我指的是2和9。
And I repeat this step.
我重复此步骤。
So now, in this case, 2 is smaller.
所以现在，在这种情况下，2较小。
So I'm going to go ahead and write 2 down.
所以我要继续写下2。
And I can cross out 2 and move my finger up to 7.
我可以划掉2并将手指移至7。
And so that's it.
就是这样。
I won't bore you with the rest of the steps.
其余步骤将不会让您感到厌烦。
It's essentially walking up.
它实际上是在走。
You have a couple of pointers and you're
你有几个指针，你是
walking up these two arrays.
走这两个阵列。
And you're writing down 1, 2, 7, 9, 11, 12, 13, 20.
您正在写下1，2，7，9，9，11，12，13，20。
And that's your merge routine.
这就是您的合并例程。
And all of the work, really, is done in the merge routine
实际上，所有工作都是在合并例程中完成的
because, other than that, the body is simply
因为除此之外，身体只是
a recursive call.
递归调用。
You have to, obviously, split the array.
显然，您必须拆分数组。
But that's fairly straightforward.
但这很简单。
If you have an array, A 0 through n-- and depending on
如果您有一个数组，则A 0到n--并取决于
whether n is odd or even-- you could
无论n是奇数还是偶数-您都可以
imagine that you set L to be A 0 n by 2 minus 1,
假设您将L设置为A 0 n 2减去1，
and R similarly.
和R类似。
And so you just split it halfway in the middle.
因此，您只需要在中间将其拆分即可。
I'll talk about that a little bit more.
我再说一点。
There's a subtlety associated with that
有一个与之相关的微妙之处
that we'll get to in a few minutes.
我们将在几分钟后到达。
But to finish up in terms of the computation of merge sort.
但是要完成合并排序的计算。
This is it.
就是这个。
The merge routine is doing most, if not all, of the work.
合并例程正在执行大部分（如果不是全部）工作。
And this two finger algorithm is going
而这两个手指算法正在
to be able to take two sorted arrays
能够接受两个排序的数组
and put them into a single sorted array
并将它们放入单个排序的数组中
by interspersing, or interleaving, these elements.
通过散布或交错这些元素。
And what's the complexity of merge
合并的复杂性是什么
if I have two arrays of size n over 2, here?
如果我有两个大小为n大于2的数组，在这里？
What do I have?
我有什么？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
PROFESSOR: n.
教授：
We'll give you a cushion, too.
我们也会给您垫子。
theta n complexity.
复杂度。
So far so good.
到现在为止还挺好。
I know you know the answer as to what
我知道你知道答案
the complexity of merge sort is.
合并排序的复杂度是。
But I'm guessing that most of you
但我猜你们大多数人
won't be able to prove it to me because I'm kind of a hard guy
无法证明给我，因为我有点硬汉
to prove something to.
证明一些东西。
And I could always say, no, I don't believe you
我总是可以说，不，我不相信你
or I don't understand.
不然我听不懂
The complexity-- and you've said this before, in class,
复杂性-您之前在课堂上已经说过了，
and I think Erik's mentioned it--
我认为Erik提到了-
the overall complexity of this algorithm is theta n log n
该算法的整体复杂度为theta n log n
And where does that come from?
那是从哪里来的？
How do you prove that?
您如何证明这一点？
And so what we'll do, now, is take a look at merge sort.
因此，我们现在要看看合并排序。
And we'll look at the recursion tree.
我们来看一下递归树。
And we'll try and-- there are many ways
我们将尝试-有很多方法
of proving that merge sort is theta n log n.
证明合并排序是the n log n。
The way we're going to do this is
我们要做的是
what's called proof by picture.
所谓的图片证明。
And it's not an established proof technique,
这不是既定的证明技术，
but it's something that is very helpful
但这很有帮助
to get an intuition behind the proof
得到证明的直觉
and why the result is true.
以及为什么结果是正确的。
And you can always take that and you
而且你总是可以接受而你
can formalize it and make this something
可以将其形式化并使其成为某种东西
that everyone believes.
每个人都相信。
And we'll also look at substitution, possibly
我们还将研究替代
in section tomorrow, for recurrence solving.
在明天的部分中，以解决复发问题。
So where we're right now is that we have a divide and conquer
因此，我们现在所处的是分而治之
algorithm that has a merge step that is theta n.
合并步骤为theta n的算法。
And so, if I just look at this structure that I have here,
因此，如果我只看这里的结构，
I can write a recurrence for merge sort
我可以为合并排序写一个循环
that looks like this.
看起来像这样。
So when I say complexity, I can say
所以当我说复杂性时，我可以说
T of n, which is the work done for n items,
T的n，这是对n个项目所做的工作，
is going to be some constant time in order
将会是一些固定的时间
to divide the array.
分割数组。
So this could be the part corresponding
所以这可能是对应的部分
to dividing the array.
划分数组。
And there's going to be two problems of size n over 2.
并且将存在两个大小大于2的问题。
And so I have 2 T of n over 2.
所以我有2 T大于2。
And this is the recursive part.
这是递归的部分。
And I'm going to have c times n, which is the merge part.
我将得到c乘以n，这是合并部分。
And that's some constant times n, which is what we have,
那就是我们所拥有的恒定时间n
here, with respect to the theta n complexity.
这里，关于theta n复杂性。
So you have a recurrence like this and I know some of you
所以你有这样的复发，我认识一些人
have seen recurrences in 6.042.
在6.042中看到了复发。
And you know how to solve this.
而且您知道如何解决此问题。
What I'd like to do is show you this recursion tree expansion
我想做的就是向您展示此递归树扩展
that, not only tells you how to solve this occurrence,
那不仅告诉您如何解决这种情况，
but also gives you a means of solving recurrences where,
而且还为您提供了一种解决重复发生的方法，
instead of having c of n, you have something else out here.
而不是c等于n，您这里还有其他内容。
You have f of n, which is a different function
您有n个f，这是一个不同的函数
from the linear function.
从线性函数。
And this recursion tree is, in my mind,
在我看来，这棵递归树是
the simplest way of arguing the theta n log n
争论then n的最简单方法
complexity of merge sort.
合并排序的复杂性。
So what I want to do is expand this recurrence out.
因此，我想做的就是扩大此重复范围。
And let's do that over here.
让我们在这里做。
So I have c of n on top.
所以我在n的c上面。
I'm going to ignore this constant factor because c of n
我将忽略此常数，因为n为c
dominates.
占主导地位。
So I'll just start with c of n.
因此，我将从n的c开始。
I want to break things up, as I do the recursion.
我想分手，就像做递归一样。
So when I go c of n, at the top level-- that's
因此，当我在n处求c时，在最高层-
the work I have to do at the merge, at the top level.
在合并中，我必须在顶层完成的工作。
And then when I go down to two smaller problems, each of them
然后当我涉及两个较小的问题时，每个问题
is size n over 2.
大小n大于2。
So I do c times n divided by 2 [INAUDIBLE].
所以我用c乘以n除以2 [听不清]。
So this is just a constant c.
所以这只是一个常数c。
I didn't want to write thetas up here.
我不想在这里写thetas。
You could.
你可以。
And I'll say a little bit more about that later.
我稍后再说更多。
But think of this cn as representing the theta n
但是认为这个cn代表theta n
complexity.
复杂。
And c is this constant.
c是这个常数。
So c times n, here. c times n over 2, here.
所以c乘以n，在这里。 c乘以n等于2。
And then when I keep going, I have c times n over 4,
然后，当我继续前进时，我得到n的c乘以4，
c times n over 4, et cetera, and so on, and so forth.
c乘以n等于4，等等，依此类推。
And when I come down all the way here,
当我一路下来
n is eventually going to become 1-- or essentially a constant--
n最终将变成1或基本上是一个常数
and I'm going to have a bunch of c's here.
我这里会有很多c。
So here's another question, that I'd like you to answer.
所以这是另一个问题，我想请你回答。
Someone tell me what the number of levels in this tree are,
有人告诉我这棵树的层数是多少，
precisely, and the number of leaves in this tree are,
确切地说，这棵树的叶子数是
precisely.
恰好。
AUDIENCE: The number of levels is log n plus 1.
听众：级别数为log n加1。
PROFESSOR: Log n plus 1.
教授：Log n加1。
Log to the base 2 plus 1.
登录以2为底的加1。
And the number of leaves?
和多少叶子？
You raised your hand back there, first.
首先，您举起手回到那里。
Number of leaves.
叶数。
AUDIENCE: I think n.
听众：我认为是。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, you're right.
教授：是的，您是对的。
You think right.
您认为正确。
So 1 plus log n and n leaves.
所以1加log n和n离开。
When n becomes 1, how many of them do you have?
当n变为1时，您有几个？
You're down to a single element, which is, by definition,
您只有一个元素，根据定义，
sorted.
排序。
And you have n leaves.
你有n片叶子。
So now let's add up the work.
现在让我们加起来。
I really like this picture because it's just
我真的很喜欢这张照片，因为它只是
so intuitive in terms of getting us the result
在获得结果方面非常直观
that we're looking for.
我们正在寻找。
So you add up the work in each of the levels of this tree.
因此，您需要在该树的每个级别中添加工作。
So the top level is cn.
因此，顶层是cn。
The second level is cn because I added 1/2 and 1/2, cn, cn.
第二个级别是cn，因为我加了1/2和1/2，cn，cn。
Wow.
哇。
What symmetry.
什么对称。
So you're doing the same amount of work modulo
因此，您正在做相同数量的模运算
the constant factors, here, with what's
恒定因素，这里是什么
going on with the c1, which we've ignored,
继续我们忽略的c1
but roughly the same amount of work in each of the levels.
但每个级别的工作量大致相同。
And now, you know how many levels there are.
现在，您知道有多少个级别。
It's 1 plus log n.
它是1加log n。
So if you want to write an equation for T of n,
因此，如果您要为n的T编写方程，
it's 1 plus log n times c of n, which is theta of n log n.
它是1加log n乘以n的c，即n log n的θ。
So I've mixed in constants c and thetas.
所以我混合了常数c和thetas。
For the purposes of this description,
为了便于说明，
they're interchangeable.
它们是可互换的。
You will see recurrences that look like this, in class.
在课堂上，您将看到类似这样的重复发生。
And things like that.
这样的事情。
Don't get confused.
不要感到困惑。
It's just a constant multiplicative factor
这只是一个恒定的乘法因子
in front of the function that you have.
在您拥有的功能之前
And it's just a little easier, I think,
我认为这要容易一些，
to write down these constant factors
写下这些恒定因素
and realize that the amount of work done
并意识到完成的工作量
is the same in each of the leaves.
每一片叶子都一样
And once you know the dimensions of this tree,
一旦知道了这棵树的尺寸，
in terms of levels and in terms of the number of leaves,
就级别和叶子数量而言，
you get your result.
你得到你的结果。
So we've looked at two algorithm, so far.
到目前为止，我们已经研究了两种算法。
And insertion sort, if you talk about numbers,
插入排序，如果您谈论数字，
is theta n squared for swaps.
是交换的平方。
Merge sort is theta n log n.
合并排序为the log n。
Here's another interesting question.
这是另一个有趣的问题。
What is one advantage of insertion sort over merge sort?
插入排序优于合并排序的一个优点是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: What does that mean?
教授：那是什么意思？
AUDIENCE: You don't have to move elements outside
听众：您不必将元素移到外面
of [INAUDIBLE].
的[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: That's exactly right.
教授：完全正确。
That's exactly right.
没错
So the two guys who answered the questions
所以两个回答问题的家伙
before with the levels, and you.
在关卡之前，还有你。
Come to me after class.
下课后过来找我。
So that's a great answer.
因此，这是一个很好的答案。
It's in-place sorting is something
就地分拣是什么
that has to do with auxiliary space.
与辅助空间有关。
And so what you see, here-- and it was a bit hidden, here.
所以您在这里看到的东西-在这里有些隐蔽。
But the fact of the matter is that you
但事实是，你
had L prime and R prime.
有L素数和R素数。
And L prime and R prime are different from L and R, which
并且L素数和R素数与L和R不同，后者
were the initial halves of the inputs to the sorting
是排序输入的最初一半
algorithm.
算法。
And what I said here is, we're going to dump this into A.
我在这里说的是，我们要将其转储到A中。
That's what this picture shows.
这就是这张图片所显示的。
This says sorted array, A. And so you
这就是说排序数组A。所以你
had to make a copy of the array-- the two halves L
必须制作数组的副本-L的两半
and R-- in order to do the recursion,
和R--为了进行递归，
and then to take the results and put them
然后把结果放进去
into the sorted array, A.
进入排序后的数组A
So you needed-- in merge sort-- you
因此，您需要-在合并排序中-
needed theta n auxiliary space.
需要的辅助空间。
So merge sort, you need theta n extra space.
因此，合并排序时，您需要额外的空间。
And the definition of in-place sorting
以及就地排序的定义
implies that you have theta 1-- constant-- auxiliary space.
表示您有theta 1（常数）辅助空间。
The auxiliary space for insertion sort
辅助排序空间
is simply that temporary variable
只是那个临时变量
that you need when you swap two elements.
交换两个元素时需要的。
So when you want to swap a couple of registers,
因此，当您想交换几个寄存器时，
you gotta store one of the values in a temporary location,
您必须将其中一个值存储在一个临时位置，
override the other, et cetera.
覆盖其他等等。
And that's the theta 1 auxiliary space for insertion sort.
这就是用于插入排序的theta 1辅助空间。
So there is an advantage of the version of insertion sort
所以插入排序的版本有一个优势
we've talked about, today, over merge sort.
今天，我们已经讨论过合并排序。
And if you have a billion elements, that's potentially
如果您有十亿个元素，则可能
something you don't want to store in memory.
您不想存储在内存中的东西。
If you want to do something really fast and do everything
如果您想快速地做某事并做所有事情
in cache or main memory, and you want
在缓存或主存储器中，并且您想要
to sort billions are maybe even trillions of items,
数十亿甚至数万亿个项目，
this becomes an important consideration.
这成为重要的考虑因素。
I will say that you can reduce the constant factor
我会说你可以减少常数因子
of the theta n.
的
So in the vanilla scheme, you could
因此，在香草方案中，您可以
imagine that you have to have a copy of the array.
假设您必须拥有阵列的副本。
So if you had n elements, you essentially
因此，如果您有n个元素，
have n extra items of storage.
有n个额外的存储空间。
You can make that n over 2 with a simple coding trick
您可以使用简单的编码技巧使n超过2
by keeping 1/2 of A.
保持A的1/2。
You can throw away one of the L's or one of the R's.
您可以扔掉L之一或R之一。
And you can get it down to n over 2.
您可以将其降低到2以上的n。
And that turns out-- it's a reasonable thing
事实证明-这是合理的事情
to do if you have a billion elements
如果您有十亿个元素，该怎么办
and you want to reduce your storage by a constant factor.
并且您希望将存储空间减少一定的比例。
So that's one coding trick.
这就是编码技巧。
Now it turns out that you can actually go further.
现在事实证明，您实际上可以走得更远。
And there's a fairly sophisticated algorithm
而且有一个相当复杂的算法
that's sort of beyond the scope of 6.006
这超出了6.006的范围
that's an in-place merge sort.
这是就地合并排序。
And this in-place merge sort is kind of
这种就地合并方式是
impractical in the sense that it doesn't do very well
就它做得不好而言，这是不切实际的
in terms of the constant factors.
就恒定因素而言。
So while it's in-place and it's still theta n log n.
因此，尽管它就位并且仍然是n n log n。
The problem is that the running time of an in-place merge sort
问题是就地合并排序的运行时间
is much worse than the regular merge sort that
比常规的合并排序要差得多
uses theta n auxiliary space.
使用辅助空间。
So people don't really use in-place merge sort.
因此人们并不真正使用就地合并排序。
It's a great paper.
这是一篇很棒的论文。
It's a great thing to read.
读起来很棒。
Its analysis is a bit sophisticated for double 0 6.
对于双精度0 6，它的分析有点复杂。
So we wont go there.
所以我们不会去那里。
But it does exist.
但是它确实存在。
So you can take merge sort, and I just
所以您可以进行合并排序，而我只是
want to let you know that you can do things in-place.
希望让您知道您可以就地做事。
In terms of numbers, some experiments we ran a few years
在数量方面，我们进行了一些实验
ago-- so these may not be completely valid
以前-因此这些可能并不完全有效
because I'm going to actually give you numbers--
因为我实际上要给你数字-
but merge sort in Python, if you write a little curve fit
但是如果您编写一些曲线拟合，则可以在Python中合并排序
program to do this, is 2.2n log n microseconds for a given n.
程序执行此操作，对于给定的n是2.2n log n微秒。
So this is the merge sort routine.
这就是合并排序例程。
And if you look at insertion sort, in Python,
如果您看一下插入排序，在Python中，
that's something like 0.2 n square microseconds.
大约是0.2 n平方微秒。
So you see the constant factors here.
因此，您在这里看到了恒定因素。
If you do insertion sort in C, which is a compiled language,
如果您使用C（一种已编译的语言）进行插入排序，
then, it's much faster.
然后，它要快得多。
It's about 20 times faster.
大约快20倍。
It's 0.01 n squared microseconds.
0.01 n平方微秒。
So a little bit of practice on the side.
因此，在侧面进行一些练习。
We do ask you to write code.
我们确实要求您编写代码。
And this is important.
这很重要。
The reason we're interested in algorithms
我们对算法感兴趣的原因
is because people want to run them.
是因为人们想要运行它们。
And what you can see is that you can actually find an n-- so
您会看到，您实际上可以找到一个n
regardless of whether you're Python or C,
无论您是Python还是C，
this tells you that asymptotic complexity is pretty important
这告诉你渐进复杂性非常重要
because, once n gets beyond about 4,000,
因为，一旦n超过4,000，
you're going to see that merge sort in Python
您将在Python中看到合并排序
beats insertion sort in C.
在C中胜过插入排序。
So the constant factors get subsumed
因此常数因素被包含在内
beyond certain values of n.
超过n的某些值。
So that's why asymptotic complexity is important.
这就是为什么渐进复杂性很重要的原因。
You do have a factor of 20, here,
你的确有20倍，
but that doesn't really help you in terms
但这并不能真正帮助您
of keeping an n square algorithm competitive.
保持n平方算法具有竞争力。
It stays competitive for a little bit longer,
它可以保持更长的竞争力，
but then falls behind.
但后来落后了。
That's what I wanted to cover for sorting.
这就是我要涵盖的排序内容。
So hopefully, you have a sense of what
因此，希望您对
happens with these two sorting algorithms.
这两种排序算法都会发生这种情况。
We'll look at a very different sorting algorithm next time,
下次我们将讨论一种非常不同的排序算法，
using heaps, which is a different data structure.
使用堆，这是不同的数据结构。
The last thing I want to do in the couple minutes I have left
我想在剩下的几分钟内做的最后一件事
is give you a little more intuition as to recurrence
让您对复发有更多的直觉
solving based on this diagram that I wrote up there.
根据我在那里写的这张图求解。
And so we're going to use exactly this structure.
因此，我们将完全使用此结构。
And we're going to look at a couple of different recurrences
我们将研究几种不同的复发
that I won't really motivate in terms
我不会真正用语言激励
of having a specific algorithm, but I'll just
具有特定算法的方法，但我只是
write out the recurrence.
写出复发。
And we'll look at the recursion tree for that.
我们将为此查看递归树。
And I'll try and tease out of you the complexity associated
我会尝试从中挑剔出相关的复杂性
with these recurrences of the overall complexity.
这些重复的整体复杂性。
So let's take a look at T of n equals 2 T of n over 2
因此，让我们看一下n中的T等于2中n的2 T
plus c n squared.
加cn平方。
Let me just call that c-- no need for the brackets.
让我称呼c--不需要括号。
So constant c times n squared.
因此常数c乘以n的平方。
So if you had a crummy merge routine,
因此，如果您的合并程序很简陋，
and it was taking n square, and you coded it up wrong.
它占用了n平方，而您将其编码错误。
It's not a great motivation for this recurrence,
这种复发不是很大的动力，
but it's a way this recurrence could have come up.
但这是复发的一种方式。
So what does this recursive tree look like?
那么，这棵递归树是什么样的呢？
Well it looks kind of the same, obviously.
好吧，看起来很像。
You have c n square; you have c n square divided by 4;
您有cn广场；您的cn平方除以4;
c n square divided by 4; c n square divided
cn平方除以4; cn平方划分
by 16, four times.
乘以16，四次
Looking a little bit different from the other one.
看起来与其他人有些不同。
The levels and the leaves are exactly the same.
级别和叶子完全相同。
Eventually n is going to go down to 1.
最终，n将降至1。
So you will see c all the way here.
因此，您将在这里看到c。
And you're going to have n leaves.
而且您将拥有n片叶子。
And you will have, as before, 1 plus log n levels.
和以前一样，您将拥有1加log n级别。
Everything is the same.
一切都一样。
And this is why I like this recursive tree formulation so
这就是为什么我喜欢这种递归树公式的原因
much because, now, all I have to do
这是因为，现在我要做的就是
is add up the work associated with each of the levels
将与每个级别相关的工作加起来
to get the solution to the recurrence.
获得复发的解决方案。
Now, take a look at what happens, here.
现在，在这里看看会发生什么。
c n square; c n square divided by 2; c n square divided by 4.
cn广场cn平方除以2; cn平方除以4。
And this is n times c.
这是n次c。
So what does that add up to?
那加起来是什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Yeah, exactly.
教授：好的。
Exactly right.
非常正确。
So if you look at what happens, here, this dominates.
因此，如果您看看发生了什么，那么这里就占主导地位。
All of the other things are actually less than that.
所有其他事情实际上都少于这个。
And you said bounded by two c n square
而你说的是两个cn平方的界限
because this part is bounded by c n square
因为这部分受cn平方限制
and I already have c n square up at the top.
并且我已经在顶部放了cn square。
So this particular algorithm that corresponds to this crummy
因此，对应于这种笨拙的特定算法
merge sort, or wherever this recurrence came from,
合并排序或这种重复发生的来源，
is a theta n squared algorithm.
是一个θ平方算法。
And in this case, all of the work done
在这种情况下，所有完成的工作
is at the root-- at the top level of the recursion.
是根源-在递归的顶层。
Here, there was a roughly equal amount
在这里，大致相等
of work done in each of the different levels.
每个不同级别完成的工作。
Here, all of the work was done at the root.
在这里，所有工作都是从根本上完成的。
And so to close up shop, here, let
所以要关闭商店，在这里，让
me just give you real quick a recurrence where
我给你一个真正的快速复发
all of the work is done at the leaves, just for closure.
所有工作都在叶子处完成，仅用于封闭。
So if I had, magically, a merge routine that actually happened
因此，如果我神奇地拥有实际上发生的合并例程
in constant time, either through buggy analysis,
在恒定的时间内，通过错误分析
or because of it was buggy, then what
还是因为它有越野车，那
does the tree look like for that?
树看起来像那样吗？
And I can think of this as being theta 1.
我可以认为这是theta 1。
Or I can think of this as being just a constant c.
或者我可以认为这仅仅是一个常数c。
I'll stick with that.
我会坚持下去。
So I have c, c, c.
所以我有c，c，c。
Woah, I tried to move that up.
哇，我试图将其调高。
That doesn't work.
那不行
So I have n leaves, as before.
所以我和以前一样有n片叶子。
And so if I look at what I have, here, I
因此，如果我看看自己拥有的东西，在这里，我
have c at the top level.
在顶层有c。
I have 2c, and so on and so forth.
我有2c，依此类推。
4c.
4c。
And then I go all the way down to nc.
然后我一直走到nc。
And so what happens here is this dominates.
因此，这里发生的事情占主导地位。
And so, in this recurrence, the whole thing runs in theta n.
因此，在这种情况下，整个过程都在theta n中运行。
So the solution to that is theta n.
因此，解决方案是theta n。
And what you have here is all of the work
您在这里拥有的全部工作
being done at the leaves.
在叶子上完成。
We're not going to really cover this theorem that gives you
我们不会真正讨论这个给您的定理
a mechanical way of figuring this out because we think
解决这一问题的机械方法，因为我们认为
the recursive tree is a better way of looking at.
递归树是一种更好的观察方法。
But you can see that, depending on what that function is,
但是您可以看到，取决于该功能是什么，
in terms of the work being done in the merge routine,
就合并例程中完成的工作而言，
you'd have different versions of recurrences.
您将有不同版本的重复发生。
I'll stick around, and people who answered questions, please
我会留下来，请回答问题的人
pick up you cushions.
拿起你的垫子。
See you next time.
下次见。